<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text</string>
    <string name="ariticle_title">Harmonica Influencers</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">The songs</string>
    <string name="article_text">
        <b>Song 1: John Mayall, \“Room to Move\”</b>
        \n
        Turning Point, a John Mayall live album from a 1969 concert at the Fillmore East, kicked me in the ass and launched my harmonica career. I was barely 15, in my first band, and \“Room to Move\” became my signature tune. I learned about breathing, pacing, and playing rhythm. The album crossed the lines between protest folk, blues, and jazz, from the pioneer of the British blues and the mentor of Eric Clapton, Jimmy Page, and Jeff Beck. It was not a well known album, and it was probably not his best album, but it was a turning point for me.
        \n
        http://www.rockument.com/blog/rockument_shows/harmonica-influencers.
        \n\n
        <b>Song 2: Alan Wilson of Canned Heat, \“On The Road Again\”</b>
        \n
        The second song I learned, at age 15, is still the most often requested when I play live. \“On the Road Again\” appeared on <i>Boogie with Canned Heat</i> in 1968. It is a remake of the 1953 Floyd Jones song of the same name, which is based on Tommy Johnson’s \“Big Road Blues\”, recorded in 1928.
        \n
        Harmonica player Alan Wilson, also known as Blind Owl, provides the distinctive falsetto as well as a harmonica performance for the ages. His tambura at the beginning and end reinforces his hypnotic one-chord drone on guitar to give it an exotic, Eastern flair. The boogie riff itself is a basic E/G/A blues chord pattern adapted from John Lee Hooker’s \“Boogie Chillen\” from 1949. But Wilson’s harmonica has a distinct country-acoustic feel that I prefer, not overly amplified as in most Chicago-style blues. The opening harmonica riff is something I play nearly every day, just to warm up.
        \n\n
        <b>Song 3: Sonny Terry with Woody Guthrie, “\Goin’ Down This Road Feelin’ Bad\”</b>
        \n
        I’ve played this song hundreds of times — with every band I’ve played in or with. Woody Guthrie recorded it with Sonny Terry (Saunders Teddell) on harmonica in 1940. Known also as \“Lonesome Road Blues\”, \”Down In The Jail On My Knees\”, \“Blowin’ Down This Road\”, and \“I Ain’t Gonna Be Treated This Way\” among other titles, this song is probably best known for its cover by the Grateful Dead, although Garcia was known to favor a version by Delaney and Bonnie.
        \n
        For me, Woody’s is the original version, and Sonny Terry is the source of my harmonica style. You can hear Sonny whooping and hollering while playing harmonica, without stopping to take a breath. Sonny could make a harmonica walk and talk at the same time. He was a musical legend, a Piedmont blues musician, long-standing partner with Brownie McGhee, and a frequent collaborator with Woody. He was invited to play at Carnegie Hall for the first \“From Spirituals to Swing\” concert in 1938. Producer John Hammond supposedly went looking for Robert Johnson in the Deep South, found out he had been murdered, and discovered blind Sonny working the juke joints. Among many strange career highlights, Sonny appeared in the movie <i>The Color Purple</i>.
        \n
        He played acoustically, not directly on the  microphone as more modern blues players did (and still do), but with enough air between his harmonica and the mic so that you can hear the wah-wah effect of his hands as he cupped and opened them around his harmonica. I enjoy playing this way, because it is the same way as playing without a mic to a small audience without amplification. I also picked up the chugging tongue-clucking chords he used for rhythm.
        \n\n
        <b>Song 4: Delbert McClinton with Bruce Channel, \“Hey Baby\”</b>
        \n
        This 45-inch single must have been in my older brother’s record collection, because I remember hearing it at age 7 in 1962 when it reached number one on the pop charts. Bruce Channel is the singer, and a young Delbert McClinton plays the harmonica.
        \n
        As a youngster I was hooked on pop music, and I probably considered this song to be one of the novelty records of the day, on a par with \“The Purple People Eater\” and \“Splish Splash\”. In any case, with this song I discovered what a harmonica was. Even at that age I was thinking about instruments. I had forgotten the song for several years until I heard NRBQ cover it, and that’s when I remembered the harmonica part.
        \n
        Texas-born Delbert McClinton went on to win four Grammy awards for rock and blues. This single launched the harmonica into modern pop music, not only for its novelty but also for the fact that John Lennon met Delbert McClinton in 1962 and asked him for tips on how to play the harmonica, just before John recorded \“Love Me Do\”.
    </string>
    <string name="add_comment">ADD COMMENT</string>

</resources>